Guide to the Joseph Conrad Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Joseph Conrad Collection
1860-1957
GEN MSS 1207
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
15.9
(40 boxes)
The Joseph Conrad Collection contains writings, correspondence, and other material by or relating to Joseph Conrad.
Conrad, Joseph, 1857-1924
Joseph Conrad (1857-1924)
Joseph Conrad was born in Poland, spent much of his childhood in Russian exile with his parents, was orphaned at an early age and reared by an uncle, lived as a young man in France, and then, after a career with the British merchant marine, became one of the major writers in English literature.
Biographical information taken from Magill's Survey of World Literature, Rev. ed. (January 2009). Additional biographical information can be found in standard print and online sources.
Scope and Contents
The Joseph Conrad Collection contains writings, correspondence, and other material by or relating to Joseph Conrad. The first group of material, bound or housed in slipcases, consists chiefly of drafts of writings by Conrad and autograph letters, signed, from Conrad to others. Most of the bindings and cases appear to have been made for the collector George T. Keating, who donated his Conrad collection to the Yale University Library in 1938. The writings in this group include autograph manuscript and typescript drafts to numerous shorter works and sections, such as "Author's Notes" and chapters of longer works. However, there are also substantial drafts, typescript, corrected, of The Arrow of Gold (1919), Nostromo (1904), and other titles. Bound correspondence features volumes of letters to Conrad's wife, and his friend, translator, and biographer, G. Jean-Aubry.
Other "loose" papers are subdivided into four groups: writings, correspondence, papers relating to Conrad, and photographs. Writings here include drafts of shorter works and sections to longer works, several French language translations, and the original autograph manuscript, corrected, of Conrad's novel, The Heart of Darkness (1899). There are separate, alphabetized runs of outgoing and incoming correspondence, with many files for English literary figures, including authors, critics, editors, and publishers, dating into the first three decades of the twentieth century. Correspondents include Arnold Bennett, Muirhead Bone, Ford Maddox Ford, John Galsworthy, Edward Garnett, G. Jean-Aubry, Archibald Marshall, Humphrey Sumner Milford, Arthur Thomas Quiller-Couch, Frank Swinnerton, and Hugh Walpole, among others.
The papers relating to Conrad consist chiefly of third-party correspondence and writings by others on or about Conrad. The largest file relates to G. Jean-Aubry and his work on Conrad. These materials include translations of writings by Conrad, biographical and bibliographical information relating to Conrad, correspondence, and printed and other material, such as clippings and ephemera. There are also many third-party letters from others to Jean-Aubry.
Typed transcriptions can be found in the collection for some writings and correspondence. When there are only transcriptions present in a file, this fact is noted (e.g. "copy") in the file-level description.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: Volumes and Cases, and Other Papers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from various sources. For more information consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 25: Restricted material. May not be seen without the permission of the appropriate curator.
Authors, Polish -- 19th century -- Archives; Authors, Polish -- 20th Century -- Archives; English literature -- 19th century; English literature -- 20th Century; Photographic prints; Authors; Adams, Elbridge L., 1866-; Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931; Benrimo, 1871-1942; Bone, Muirhead, Sir, 1876-1953; Candler, Edmund, 1874-1926; Colvin, Sidney, 1845-1927; Conrad, Jessie, 1873-1936; Conrad, Joseph, 1857-1924; Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939; Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933; Garnett, Edward, 1868-1937; Holland, Bernard, 1856-1926; Jean-Aubry, G. (Georges), 1882-1950; Keating, George T., 1892-; Marshall, Archibald, 1866-1934; Milford, Humphrey Sumner, Sir, 1877-1952; Pinker, James B.; Quiller-Couch, Arthur, 1863-1944; Swinnerton, Frank, 1884-1982; Visiak, E. H. (Edward Harold); Walpole, Hugh, 1884-1941; T. Fisher Unwin (Firm)
- Volumes and Cases, 1860-1938; 9.22; (23 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Folder titles transcribed from manuscripts or containers.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Advt Matters about The Rover for Mr. Fisher Unwin's List, 1922 November 9 (Box 1)
  - Anatole France, undated (Box 1)
  - A propos of A. Daudet, 1898 January 19 (Box 1)
  - The Arrow of Gold, Author's Note, 1920 October (Box 1)
  - The Arrow of Gold, 1918 June; 2 (Box 2)
  - Autocracy and War, 1905 (Box 3)
  - Autograph Letters, 1902-1924; 2 (Box 3)
  - Autograph Letters in French and English, 1899-1913 (Box 4)
  - A Censorship of Plays: An Appreciation, 1907 (Box 4)
  - Chance: A Tale in Two Parts, Part I, undated (Box 4)
  - Chance: A Tale in Two Parts, Part II, undated (Box 5)
  - A Conrad Memorial Library at Yale, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Conrad's Masters Certificate, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Conrad's Oath of Allegiance, 1886-1934
  - The Crime of Partition, 1918 December (Box 6)
  - Draft of Speech to be Made at the Lifeboat Institution at the 99th Annual Meeting, 1923 April 17 (Box 6)
  - The End of the Tether, 1913 (Box 6)
  - Falk: A Reminiscence, undated (Box 6)
  - "Foreward" to Turgenev: A Study by Edward Garnett, 1860, 1917 (Box 7)
    Includes Un dernier mot sur l'émancipation des serfs par N. Tourgueneff, printed version (Paris: A. Frank, 1860)
  - Gaspar, the Strong Man: Film-Play (From "Gaspar-Ruiz"), 1920 (Box 7)
  - Geography, 1923 (Box 7)
  - Henry James: An Appreciation, 1904 (Box 8)
  - The Husband, 1901 June 18 (Box 8)
  - The Inn of the Two Witches: A Find, 1913 (Box 8)
  - Joseph Conrad a G. Jean Aubry, 1917-1924; 2 (Box 9)
  - "Joseph Conrad as a Ship's Prow" by Mrs. Joseph Conrad, printed version, T.P.s and Cassell's Weekly, 1927 June 25 (Box 10)
  - "Joseph Conrad in The East" by Richard Curle, 1922, 1928 (Box 10)
  - "Joseph Conrad's Confessions" by G. Jean-Aubry, 1921, undated (Box 10)
  - Joseph Conrad's Diary, 1926 (Box 11)
  - Joseph Conrad's Letters to His Wife, 1916-1924 (Box 11)
  - The Laugh, 1917 (Box 11)
  - The Nigger of the "Narcissus," A Tale of the Sea, printed vesion (London: William Heinemann, 1921), signed, 2 (Box 12)
  - Nostromo, undated (Box 12)
  - Nostromo, Note, 1917 (Box 13)
  - Nostromo, Part Third, undated (Box 13)
  - Notes on Life & Letters, printed version (London: J. M. Dent, 1921), signed and annotated (Box 13)
  - Notes on Life & Letters, printed version (London: J. M. Dent, 1921), "Jessie's copy" (Box 14)
  - Notes on Life & Letters, Author's Note, 1920 May (Box 14)
  - Offer of Knighthood, Original Drawing by Conrad for Arrow of Gold, 1924
  - Original Autograph Letters of Conrad to Madam Poradowska, 1890-1920; 2 (Box 15)
  - Original Discharges Issued, 1878-1894 (Box 16)
  - Ottago Letters, 1888-1889 (Box 16)
  - An Outpost of Progress, 1896 July (Box 16)
  - Outside Literature, 1922 (Box 16)
  - Poland Revisited, undated (Box 17)
  - Preface to "Into the East: Notes on Burma and Malaya" by Richard Curle, 1922 (Box 17)
  - Preface to the Vol of Selected Stories, undated (Box 17)
  - The Princess and the Page: A True Fairy Tale for Grown-up Princesses, 1896 (Box 17)
  - References, 1880-1893 (Box 17)
  - The Rescue, 1919
  - Rita Lastaola: A Tale, 1919 (Box 18)
    General
    See also: Volumes and Cases, Arrow of Gold, Boxes 1-2
  - Romance, circa 1900 (Box 18)
  - The Rover, 1921-1922 (Box 18)
  - The Secret Agent, printed version (London: Methuen & Co., 1907), signed and annotated, 2 (Box 19)
  - The Secret Agent, Author's Note, 1920 (Box 20)
  - A Set of Six, Author's Note, 1920 (Box 20)
  - The Shadow-line, 1915-1920; 2 (Box 20)
  - The Smile of Fortune: A Harbour Story, undated (Box 21)
  - Stephen Crane: A Note Without Dates, printed version, The London Mercury, 1919 (Box 21)
  - Suspense, circa 1923-1924; 2 (Box 21)
  - The "Torrens": A Personal Tribute, 1923 (Box 22)
  - Tradition, 1919-1920 (Box 22)
  - The Warriors Soul, 1916-1919, undated; 4 (Box 22)
  - Oversize
    - Conrad's Oath of Allegiance, 1886-1934 (Box 23 (Oversize))
    - Offer of Knighthood, Original Drawing by Conrad for Arrow of Gold, 1924 (Box 23 (Oversize))
    - The Rescue, 1919 (Box 23 (Oversize))
- Other Papers, 1862-1957; 6.68; (17 boxes)
  Organized into four sub-groupings: Writings, Correspondence, Papers Relating to Conrad, and Photographs.
  - Writings
    - Almayer's Folly, Chap XI, No. I (photostat), undated (Box 24)
    - Arrow of Gold, autograph drawing, undated (Box 24)
    - Chance, leaf "154", undated (Box 24)
    - Christmas Day at Sea, French translation, Noël à la Mer, printed version, corrected, undated (Box 24)
    - The Dover Patrol, autograph manuscript and typescript fragment, undated (Box 24)
    - The End of the Tether, French translation, Jusqu'au bout de la chaine, printed version, corrected, undated (Box 24)
    - Geography and Some Explorers, French translation, Géographie et de quelques explorateurs, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 24)
    - A Glance at Two Books, French translation, Coup d'oeil sur deux livres, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 24)
    - Heart of Darkness, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 25)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted material. May not be seen without the permission of the appropriate curator.
    - Heart of Darkness, autograph manuscript, corrected (photocopy), undated; 5 (Box 26)
    - The Idiots, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 27)
    - The Lagoon, typescript, corrected, 1896; 2 (Box 27)
    - Lord Jim, Author's Note, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 27)
    - The Mirror of the Sea, Author's Note, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 27)
    - The Mirror of the Sea, French translation, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 27)
    - The Mirror of the Sea, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 27)
    - The Nature of a Crime, Chapter Five fragment, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 27)
    - The Nature of a Crime, Preface, autograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, undated; 2 (Box 27)
    - Nostromo, drafts and fragments, autograph manuscript and typescript, corrected, 1904, undated; 6 (Box 27)
    - Notebook, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 27)
    - The Planter of Malata, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 27)
    - The Princess and the Page: A True Fairy Tale for Grown-Up Princesses, typescript carbon, undated (Box 27)
    - Proust as Creator, typescript, undated (Box 27)
    - The Rescue: A Romance of the Shallows, Part First: The Man and the Brig, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 27)
    - The Rover, fragments, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated; 4 (Box 27)
    - The Secret Agent, Author's Note, autograph manuscript, corrected (photocopy), undated (Box 27)
    - The Shorter Stories of Joseph Conrad, Preface, typescript, corrected, undated; 2 (Box 27)
    - Speech Delivered by Joseph Conrad at The Lifeboat Institution..., typescript carbon, circa 1923 (Box 27)
    - Stephen Crane, French translation, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 27)
    - Sur la mort de Conrad, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 27)
    - Suspense, French translation, Angoisse, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated; 2 (Box 28)
    - Suspense, three leaves, typescript, corrected, 1926, undated; 3 (Box 28)
    - The Torrens, fragment, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 28)
    - The Torrens, French translation, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 28)
    - Typhoon, leaf, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 28)
    - Under Western Eyes, draft, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated; 13 (Box 28)
    - Under Western Eyes, draft, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated; 20 (Box 29)
    - Under Western Eyes, draft, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated; 5 (Box 30)
    - The Weight of Her Burden, autograph manuscript, corrected, undated (Box 30)
    - The Weight of Her Burden, French translation, Le poids de la charge, autograph manscript, corrected, undated (Box 30)
    - Untitled, autograph manuscript notes, undated (Box 30)
  - Correspondence
    Organized into two subdivisions: Outgoing Correspondence and Incoming Correspondence.
    - Outgoing Correspondence
      Arranged alphabetically by name.
      - Allen, J. A., 1924 January 29 (Box 31)
      - Archer, William, 1917 July 18 (Box 31)
      - Aubry, F., 1921-1924; 3 (Box 31)
      - Bashford, Lindsay, undated (Box 31)
      - Batty, Mr., 1918 July 19 (Box 31)
      - Benrimo, J. H., 1922 October 21 (Box 31)
      - Blodgett, Mr., 1920 January 20 (Box 31)
      - Bone, David, 1922 May 24 (Box 31)
      - Brunnow, Janina (copy), 1908 June 20 (Box 31)
      - Chesson, Wilfred Hugh, 1898 January 16 (Box 31)
      - Colvin, Sidney, 1905-1924; 16 (Box 31)
      - "Conal", undated (Box 31)
      - Davray, Henry D. (copies), 1900, 1913; 2 (Box 31)
      - Dawson, Ernest, 1907 January 3 (Box 31)
      - Divorie, Fernand, 1922 September 25 (Box 31)
      - Doubleday and Company, Inc., undated (Box 31)
      - Evans, C. S., 1920 September (Box 31)
      - Everitt, S. A. (copy), 1918 February 18 (Box 31)
      - Ford, Christina, undated (Box 31)
      - Ford, Elsie Martindale, 1900-1920; 2 (Box 31)
      - Ford, Ford Maddox, 1898-1924, undated; 9 (Box 31)
      - Garnett, Edward, 1895-1919; 20 (Box 32)
      - Goodenough, Admiral (copy), 1920 September 25 (Box 32)
      - Graham, R. B. C., 1899 February 8 (Box 32)
      - Gwynne, H. A., 1905 October (Box 32)
      - Harrison, Austin, 1910 September 30 (Box 32)
      - Hind, Charles, 1898 April 16 (Box 32)
      - Holt, Lawrence Durning, 1920 July (Box 32)
      - Hutchins, Robert M., 1923 May 7 (Box 32)
      - Ibañez, Vicente Blasco, 1923 March 21 (Box 32)
      - Janvier, Meredith, 1922 December 18 (Box 32)
      - Jean-Aubry, G., 1917-1924 (Box 32)
      - Jones, Robert (copy), 1919 December 10 (Box 32)
      - Keating, George T., 1920-1924; 8 (Box 32)
      - Kliszczewski, Spiridion (copies), 1885-1886; 2 (Box 32)
      - Knopf, Alfred A. (copy), 1913 July 20 (Box 32)
      - Land and Water (copy), 1918 December 12 (Box 32)
      - Long, John Edward, 1909 March 20 (Box 32)
      - Lucas, E. V., 1909 June 23 (Box 32)
      - Maas, William, 1911 December 23 (Box 32)
      - Martindale, Mrs., 1903-1906 (Box 32)
      - Marwood, Arthur, 1915 April 30 (Box 32)
      - Marwood, Caroline, 1918 May 11 (Box 32)
      - Methuen & Co., Ltd. (copies), 1913 March (Box 32)
      - Oswestrian (copy), 1922 October 25 (Box 32)
      - Pinker, Eric J., 1922 July 20 (Box 32)
      - Pinker, James B., 1902-1920, undated; 3 (Box 32)
      - Pinker, James B., Mrs., 1921-1922 (Box 32)
      - Pomeranski, Stefan (copies), 1927 June 28 (Box 33)
      - Roberts, Mr., 1919 June 26 (Box 33)
      - Ruyters, André, 1913-1919; 2 (Box 33)
      - Sanderson, Edward Lancelot; Sanderson, Helen, 1896-1922; 6 (Box 33)
      - Séligmann-Lui, Mlle, 1910 August 10 (Box 33)
      - Strachey, John St. Loe (copies), 1924 May (Box 33)
      - Swinnerton, Frank Arthur (copy), 1924 March 25 (Box 33)
      - Symons, Arthur, 1918 January 30 (Box 33)
      - Thys, Albert, 1889-1890; 3 (Box 33)
      - Tyska, Marie, 1890-1892 (Box 33)
      - Unwin, T. Fisher, 1895-1897, undated; 11 (Box 33)
      - Ward, Amelia (copy), 1924 May 24 (Box 33)
      - Weston, J. Vernon (copy), 1896 May 26 (Box 33)
      - Willard, Mrs., 1916-1924; 2 (Box 33)
      - Winawer, Bruno (copies), 1921-1924 (Box 33)
      - Wise, Thomas J., undated (Box 33)
      - Zagorski, Charles; Zagorska, Angèle (copies), 1890-1899 (Box 33)
      - Zagorski, Karola; Zagorska, Angèle (copies), 1914-1924 (Box 33)
      - Zeromski, Stefan (copy), 1923 March 23 (Box 33)
      - Unidentified, 1904-1917, undated; 5 (Box 33)
    - Incoming Correspondence
      - Bashford, Lindsay, undated (Box 34)
      - Bennett, Arnold, 1923-1924 (Box 34)
      - Bobrowski, Kazimierz, 1869 (Box 34)
      - Bone, Muirhead, 1924, undated (Box 34)
      - Brownrigg, Douglas Egremont Robert, 1916 October 13 (Box 34)
      - Buls, Charles François Gommaire, 1895 May 11 (Box 34)
      - Chesson, Wilfred Hugh, 1898 January 13 (Box 34)
      - Davies, Charles Llewelyn, 1917 June 6 (Box 34)
      - Delcommune, Camille, 1890 September 6 (Box 34)
      - Ford, Ford Maddox, 1923-1924 (Box 34)
      - Galsworthy, John, 1921 February 10 (Box 34)
      - Garnett, Edward, 1906-1923; 3 (Box 34)
      - Gide, André (copies), 1912-1924 (Box 34)
      - Gillet, Louis, 1919 November 5 (Box 34)
      - Gwynne, H. A., 1905 October (Box 34)
      - Holt, Lawrence Durning, 1920 July (Box 34)
      - Ibañez, Vicente Blasco, 1923 March 10 (Box 34)
      - Jean-Aubry, G., 1917-1924 (Box 34)
      - Keating, George T., 1924 May 20 (Box 34)
      - Korzeniowska, Regina, 1865 (Box 34)
      - Lenormand, Henri Rene, undated (Box 34)
      - London, Jack (copy), 1915 June 4 (Box 34)
      - Marris, Carlos M., 1909-1910 (Box 34)
      - Marshall, Archibald, 1924 March 9 (Box 34)
      - McCullagh, Francis, 1924 June (Box 34)
      - Methuen & Co., Ltd., 1913 (Box 34)
      - Milford, Humphrey Sumner, 1924 March 6 (Box 34)
      - Moxon, Thomas F., 1917 March 13 (Box 34)
      - Pinker, Eric J., 1924 February 4 (Box 34)
      - Poradowska, Marguerite [Gachet], 1907 April 26 (Box 34)
      - Pulman, Adam Mareck, 1872 March 17 (Box 34)
      - Putnam, George Palmer, 1919 November 28 (Box 34)
      - Quiller-Couch, Arthur Thomas, 1897 December 30 (Box 34)
      - Raymond-Duval, Philibert H., 1909 March 18 (Box 34)
      - St. Clair, William Graeme, 1917 April 5 (Box 34)
      - Sanderson, Mrs. Katherine W., 1896 March 6 (Box 34)
      - Schlumberger, Jean, 1915 January 31 (Box 34)
      - Searle, Townley, 1923 December 24 (Box 34)
      - Société des gends des lettres, 1916 September 4 (Box 34)
      - Stileman, Harry Hampson, 1916 September 27 (Box 34)
      - Swinnerton, Frank Arthur, 1924 April 26 (Box 34)
      - Walpole, Hugh, 1923 January 9 (Box 34)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 34)
  - Papers Relating to Conrad
    - Adams, Elbridge L., 1924 November 12 (Box 34)
    - [Adams, Harriet], undated (Box 34)
    - Aimery de Pierrebourg, Marguerite (Thomas-Galline), 1936 August 16 (Box 34)
    - Aubry, André, n.y. March 29 (Box 34)
    - Aubry, Frederic Ferdinand, 1931 April 3 (Box 34)
    - Aubry, Mme Frederic Ferdinand, 1924 August 8 (Box 34)
    - Barker, Ambrose G., 1925 (Box 34)
    - Barrière, Jean Bertrand, 1948 March 31; 2 (Box 34)
    - Batier, Joseph, 1929 August 29 (Box 34)
    - Bauer, Gerard, 1937 May 24 (Box 34)
    - Beard, E., 1883 April 3 (Box 34)
    - Bel, Henri, 1925 August 17 (Box 34)
    - Bendz, Ernst Paulus, 1927 September 25 (Box 34)
    - Bielanska, Carolina, 1925-1927 (Box 34)
    - Blyth Brothers & Co., 1931 July 7 (Box 34)
    - Bobrowski, Stanislaw S., 1925 August 23 (Box 34)
    - Bobrowski, Tadeusz, undated (Box 34)
    - Bone, David William, 1928 April 19 (Box 34)
    - Borren, Charles van den, 1925-1947 (Box 34)
    - Bosco, Henri, 1956 March 31 (Box 34)
    - Boulteron, Marcel, 1947-1956; 2 (Box 34)
    - Bryce, Monson, 1927 December 15 (Box 34)
    - Busquet, Raoul, 1927 May (Box 34)
    - Butler, Deidre, 1957 January 15 (Box 34)
    - Cadot, Raoul, 1932-1933 (Box 35)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1924 November 12 (Box 35)
    - Capes, M., 1925 July (Box 35)
    - Carré, Louis, 1946 July 24 (Box 35)
    - Caumartin, Pierre, 1946-1947, undated (Box 35)
    - Chassé, Charles, 1924 October 16 (Box 35)
    - Chesson, Wilfred Hugh, 1924 December 11 (Box 35)
    - Clark, Barrett Harper, 1924 November 13 (Box 35)
    - Clarke, Harold, undated (Box 35)
    - Clifford, Hugh Charles, 1925 (Box 35)
    - Colgate, Henry A., 1928 February 17 (Box 35)
    - Colmain, Jean, 1925-1926 (Box 35)
    - Colvin, Sidney, 1924-1925; 2 (Box 35)
    - Conrad, Jessie (George), 1903-1933; 16 (Box 35)
    - Conrad, Joseph, 1920-1957, undated; 4 (Box 35)
    - Cooper, H. F. T., 1926 February 8 (Box 35)
    - Cornetz, Victor, 1929 February 4 (Box 35)
    - Cottez, de [Lorvette?], 1947 November 14 (Box 35)
    - Craig, E. C., 1924 October 10 (Box 35)
    - Craig, James, 1924-1925 (Box 35)
    - Cross, Wilbur Lucius, undated (Box 35)
    - Curle, Richard, 1924-1928; 3 (Box 35)
    - Dawson, Ernest, Major, 1927 February (Box 35)
    - DeCroix, Madeleine, 1956 March 25 (Box 35)
    - Delhon, Pierre, 1925; 2 (Box 35)
    - Derezinska, Helena, undated (Box 35)
    - Desmarais, Jacques, 1932 December 10 (Box 35)
    - Doubleday, Page & Co., 1925-1927; 3 (Box 35)
    - Doubleday, Russell, 1927 September 21 (Box 35)
    - Douglas, Norman, 1924 November 30 (Box 35)
    - Ducreux, Madelaine, [1956?] March 21 (Box 35)
    - Dumas, Joel, 1932 April 24 (Box 35)
    - Duncan, Archibald, 1884 October 19 (Box 35)
    - Durrant, Kate, 1925 October 13 (Box 35)
    - Esko, Stanislaw, 1927 June 28 (Box 36)
    - Esnouf, Auguste, 1931-1933; 4 (Box 36)
    - Espagnat, Georges d', 1936, 1946 (Box 36)
    - Ford, Ford Maddox, 1909-1938; 4 (Box 36)
    - The Four Seas Company, 1928 March 15 (Box 36)
    - Francheschi, Jean, 1926-1927 (Box 36)
    - Freslon, B., 1947 July 22 (Box 36)
    - Gachet, Alice, 1924-1925 (Box 36)
    - Gachet, Jean, 1933 October 21 (Box 36)
    - Galsworthy, John, 1924 September 15 (Box 36)
    - Garbert, G., 1931 July 6 (Box 36)
    - Gardiner, Gordon, 1925 February 3 (Box 36)
    - Garnett, Edward, 1925-1928; 4 (Box 36)
    - Gebethner i Wolff, 1927 March 30 (Box 36)
    - Gee, John Archer, 1939 (Box 36)
    - Gérard, A., 1930 July 2 (Box 36)
    - Gernez, Thérèse, 1956 April 10 (Box 36)
    - Gide, André Paul Guillaume, 1924, 1927 (Box 36)
    - Gillet, Louis, 1924-1927 (Box 36)
    - Girard, Pierre, 1947 July 18 (Box 36)
    - Gissing, Alfred Charles, 1926-1927 (Box 36)
    - Gissing, Gabrielle (Fleury), 1925 December 27 (Box 36)
    - Gissing, George Robert (copy?), 1903 June 3 (Box 36)
    - Gordan, John Dozier, 1938-1947 (Box 36)
    - Grandchamp, PIerre, 1946-1947 (Box 36)
    - Grydzewski, Mieczyslaw, 1949 June 10 (Box 36)
    - Guébels, Léon, 1925-1927 (Box 36)
    - Guéritte, Alfred, 1948-1950 (Box 36)
    - Guéritte, Roger, 1956 April 15 (Box 36)
    - Haffner, Léon, 1946 October 14 (Box 36)
    - Harrold, J. B., 1925 August 8 (Box 36)
    - Herzberg, Max John, 1924 November 24 (Box 36)
    - Hodgson & Co., 1927 (Box 36)
    - Holt, Lawrence Duming, 1925 August 14 (Box 36)
    - Hope, F. E., 1928 March 7 (Box 36)
    - Hope, G. F. W., 1928 March 7 (Box 36)
    - Hugon, E. Desdemaines, 1924-1925 (Box 36)
    - Humières, Robert, vicomte d', 1907 April 26 (Box 36)
    - Jaïs, Lucien, 1956 March 20 (Box 36)
    - James, Henry, 1926 December 19 (Box 36)
    - Janvier, Meredith, 1920 May 26 (Box 36)
    - Jean-Aubry, G., 1922-1934, undated; 16 (Box 37)
    - Jean-Aubry, G., 1921-1939; 6 (Box 38)
    - Kanters, Robert, 1947 October 15 (Box 38)
    - Keating, George T., 1925-1937; 2 (Box 38)
    - Kenyon, Charles Frederick, 1924 December 23 (Box 38)
    - Kinkead, Alice S., 1926 March 22 (Box 38)
    - Kipling, Rudyard, 1927 January 10 (Box 38)
    - Kliszczewski, Spiridion, 1924-1925 (Box 38)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1924 November 13 (Box 38)
    - Kridl, Manfred, 1928 (Box 38)
    - Laloux, Jules, 1956 March 20 (Box 38)
    - Langlois, Paul, 1931 June 21 (Box 38)
    - Lawrence, T. E. (Thomas Edward), undated (Box 38)
    - Lecomte, Georges Charles, 1925 March 20 (Box 38)
    - Le Dantec, Yves Gérard, 1947-1956; 2 (Box 38)
    - Leger, Alexis Saint-Leger, 1947 September 19 (Box 38)
    - Le Goffic, Charles, 1930-1931 (Box 38)
    - Lehmann, John, 1947 October 21 (Box 38)
    - Loumeau, Eugénie (Renouf), undated (Box 38)